He knows every scale.
Lyle, Lyle, Crocodile is a comedy, family, music film directed by Josh Gordon.
When the Primm family moves to New York City, their young son Josh
struggles to adapt to his new school and new friends.
All of that changes when he discovers Lyle — a singing crocodile who loves
baths, caviar and great music — living in the attic of his new home.
But when Lyle’s existence is threatened by evil neighbor Mr.
Grumps, the Primms must band together to show the world that
family can come from the most unexpected places.
Lyle (voice), played by Shawn Mendes.
Josh Primm, played by Winslow Fegley.
Hector P. Valenti, played by Javier Bardem.
Katie Primm, played by Constance Wu.
Joseph Primm, played by Scoot McNairy.
Alistair Grumps, played by Brett Gelman.
Lyle, Lyle, Crocodile is a 2022 American live-action animated musical fantasy comedy film
directed by Will Speck and Josh Gordon from a screenplay by William Davies.
Produced by Columbia Pictures and distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing, it is an adaptation of the
children's story of the same name and its predecessor The House on East 88th Street by Bernard Waber.
The plot focuses on a family who moves to New York City, where their struggling son befriends an
anthropomorphic crocodile, Lyle, who can communicate verbally only by singing.
The son tries to protect Lyle from the rest of the world.
The film stars Shawn Mendes as Lyle's singing voice, alongside Javier Bardem,
Constance Wu, Winslow Fegley, Scoot McNairy, and Brett Gelman.
Lyle, Lyle, Crocodile was released in the United States
on October 7, 2022, by Columbia Pictures.
The film received generally mixed reviews from critics and grossed $111 million.
The film explores themes of crocodile, musical, based on
children's book, outsider, live action and animation.
The tone is lighthearted.